(ナルト)多重影分身の術！
Multi Shadow Clone Jutsu!
ハッ！
《クソッ！》
Damn it!
(カカシ)ま… そう焦るなって。
Hey, don't be so impatient.
(カカシ)修業は順調だよ。
あとは 時間の問題だ。
Your training is going well.
Now it's only a matter of time.
時間の問題なら もっともっと➡
If it's just a matter of time,
then you should let me
train nonstop.
修業を続けさせてくれたって
いいじゃねえか！
(カカシ)ん～ お前がタフなのは
わかってんだけどさ…。
I know you're tough, but...
(ヤマト)ボク… ボクなら
いつだって… 大丈夫。
I-I'm ready to go... anytime.
I'm okay!
ヤマト隊長… 怖いってばよ。
C-Captain Yamato...
You're scaring me.
Once I fly,
habataitara
I won't be coming back, I said.
modorena ito itte
And I set out.
mezashita no wa
For that blue, blue sky.
aoi aoi ano sora
I haven't learned "sadness" yet.
kanashimi wa mada oboerarezu
And I'm just starting to grasp "misery".
setsunasa wa ima tsukami hajimeta
Even this feeling I hold towards you.
anata e to idaku kono kanjou mo
Is now turning into "words".
ima kotoba ni wakatteku
Waking up from the dream of this unknown world.
michi naru sekai no yume kara mezamete
I spread these wings and fly.
kono hane wo hiroge tobi datsu
Once I fly,
habataitara
I won't be coming back, I said.
modorena ito itte
And I set out.
mezashita no wa
For that blue, blue sky.
aoi aoi ano sora
Knowing I'll find the answer,
tsuki nuketara
If I pierce through it.
mitsukaru to shitte
if I break free,
furikiru hodo
From that blue, blue sky.
aoi aoi ano sora
Under the Starry Sky
(角都)次は お前が持て。
You carry him for a while.
(飛段)おいおいおい
金 金言ってんのは テメエだろ！
Hey, hey, hey.
You're the one always
talking about money.
You carry him all the way.
最後まで テメエが運べ！
大事な賞金首だろ。
He's your precious bounty, right?
What's with that look?
なんだよ！
その めんどくせえ目はよぉ！
(角都)お前は いつか必ず
オレが殺してやる。
I'm definitely going to kill you someday.
I told you, don't give me that... Kakuzu.
(飛段)だから
それをオレに言うかよ… 角都！
ハッ！ ハッ！ ハッ！ ハッ！
Oh, he's doing fine.
I guess he didn't need my food pills.
(サクラ)なんだ…
元気にやってるじゃない。
兵糧丸なんて いらなかったかな？
I think he does.
(サイ)そうでもないと 思いますよ。
うわ… やだ～ ちょっと
いつから そこにいんのよ!?
Hey!
How long have you been there?
Quite a while before you came.
サクラが来る ずっと前から…。
No way!
I had no idea...
ウソ！ 全然 気づかなかった…
アンタ 存在感なさすぎ！
I didn't even sense your presence.
アハ… すみません…。
I'm sorry.
More importantly, that training
is a lot tougher than it looks.
それより あの修業
見た目 以上に ハードですよ。
Naruto isn't all that skillful
from my viewpoint.
ボクの目から見ても
ナルトは 器用なほうじゃない。
He must sustain complete focus
その彼が
限界に近い影分身を使いながら➡
while using Shadow Clones
nearly to his limit.
集中力を 維持しなければ
ならないんだから…。
疲労の度合いは 通常の修業とは
桁外れでしょうね。
The degree of fatigue
must be extraordinary
compared to that of normal training.
Yes... That's right...
ええ… そうよね…。
That's...
(サイ)…と。
ん？
what it said in this book...
"BASICS OF CHANGE IN CHAKRA NATURE"
…この本に書いてありました。
隠すことないのに。
You didn't have to hide anything.
I thought you'd be appalled
to learn...
(サイ)また 本の知識に頼ってと
あきれられるかと…。
I'm still relying on
the knowledge of books.
やっぱり…。
I knew it...
フフフ… ごめん そうじゃないの
そういうのは いいのよ。
I'm sorry.
That's not what I meant.
It's perfectly fine.
After all, you read up on it
だって 仲間のことが
心配だから調べたんでしょう。
because you're worried
about your friends, right?
Books come in handy at times like that.
本はね そういうときにこそ
役に立つのよ。
You actually do have
a nice side to you.
アンタ 優しいとこ あるんじゃない。
What? I'm nice...?
えっ！ ボクが優しい…。
Okay, let's go
so we won't interfere with his training.
さぁ 修業の邪魔にならないように
私たちは行きましょう。
I guess they shaped up into
a good team while I was away.
《オレのいない間に いいチームに
まとまってたのかな？》
Well, that's good.
《ま いいことだよね》
ハァ ハァ ハァ ハァ…。
はっ！
Naruto!
ナルト～！
Break the Shadow Clone Jutsu for a bit
いったん 影分身を解くんだ。
and mull over the results
of your current training.
これまでの修業の成果を
反芻しながらな。
Accumulate your experience.
(カカシ)経験値の蓄積だ！
オッス！
Right!
So? Can you feel it?
どうだ？ 実感あるか？
I've still got a ways to go.
この程度じゃ まだだ…。
I'm going to continue the training...
修業を続けるってばよ…。
You're overdoing it, I tell you.
だから ムリしすぎなんだって。
それは？
サクラからの差し入れだ。
What's that?
Sakura brought it for you.
These are food pills...
and there's a note inside.
兵糧丸と メモが入ってる。
Eat one of my special food pills
and keep up the training. - Sakura
Sakura-chan...
サクラちゃん…。
ハハハ！ サクラちゃんの手作り兵糧丸
いただくってばよ！
Sakura-chan's home-made food pills.
Let's eat!
まずっ!! って サクラちゃん！
Sakura-chan, these are totally inedible.
とてもじゃねえが
食えねえってばよ。
おし！ 修業再開だ！
Okay, time to continue training!
Multi Shadow Clone Jutsu!
多重影分身の術！
はっ！
はっ！ はっ！
《フフッ あのナルトが 修業を
こんなに続けられるのも➡
I bet Naruto has been able to
continue training
きっと 私の兵糧丸のおかげね》
because of my food pills.
W-Wow!
す すごい…。
(カカシ)ナルト！
少しは休憩したらどうだ？
Naruto! Why don't you take
a little break?
I can't catch up to Sasuke
if I throw in the towel now!
こんなんで 音を上げてたんじゃ➡
いつまでたっても
サスケにゃ追いつけねえってばよ！
"MEDICINAL HERBS"
Well, if it isn't Sakura.
(イルカ)サクラじゃないか！
Oh, Iruka-sensei.
(サクラ)あぁ！ イルカ先生！
(イルカ)いや～ ナルトも
たいしたもんだよな。
Wow, Naruto sure is something else.
He did a great job during
the village's dilemma.
里のピンチに大活躍だもんな。
I did, too!
私だって活躍しました。
なんちゃって。
Just kidding.
ハハハ すまん すまん。
Sorry, sorry.
You've become
Tsunade-sama's apprentice, after all.
サクラも 綱手様の弟子になったし➡
I'm so proud to have had
such excellent students.
優秀な生徒を持ったオレは
鼻が高いよ。
My drop-out students are
particularly lovable.
特に おちこぼれの生徒は
かわいいもんさ。
Even now, Naruto's continuing with
training that only he can do, right?
今だって ナルトにしかできない
すごい修業を続けてるんだろ？
That's really something.
たいしたもんだ。
I was excellent right from the start.
私は 最初から優秀でしたからね。
Sorry I wasn't a lovable student.
かわいい生徒じゃなくて
すみませんでした。
Oh, come on.
You sure are giving me grief today.
おいおい 今日は やけに絡むなぁ。
But he sure got stronger.
エヘヘッ。 でも ホント アイツは強くなった。
Yeah. He's changed.
Everyone's changing.
あぁ 変わった。
みんな変わっていく。
My students are growing up
strong and steadfast.
(イルカ)強く たくましく
オレの生徒は成長していくんだ。
(イズモ)ん？ あれは…。
What's that?
I see...
(綱手)そうか…。
あの地陸までも…。
They even got Chiriku, huh...?
自分は ちょうど巡警に出ていて➡
I was out on patrol...
帰ってきたときには もう…。
and by the time I returned,
it was too late.
(シズネ)おそらく 暁の連中➡
It was most likely the guys
from the Akatsuki.
They're probably going one by one
to locations in the Land of Fire
火ノ国で
人柱力のいそうな場所を➡
where there might be a Jinchuriki.
しらみつぶしに
してるのでしょう。
ついに… 来ましたね。
Finally they've come.
We won't let them out
of the Land of Fire.
火ノ国から逃がすな。
Contact the twenty newly formed
platoons immediately!
新編成した 二十小隊に
ただちに連絡しろ！
That's all I have to say.
話は ここまでだ。
Does anyone have any questions?
何か質問がある者は いるか？
What is it?
何だ？
Chiriku, a former member
of the Guardian Shinobi Twelve,
(アスマ)あそこには
元 守護忍十二士の➡
should be there.
地陸がいるはずです。
彼は どうなったんです？
What happened to him?
地陸様は ソヤツらの手にかかり…➡
Chiriku-sama died by their hands.
亡くなりました。
Chiriku was killed?
It can't be...
《あの地陸が… バカな！》
For the pride of the Hidden Leaf,
and most of all,
(綱手)木ノ葉の威信にかけても➡
何より 火ノ国の安全のためにも➡
for the safety of the Land of Fire,
we must not let them rampage
any further.
ヤツらを これ以上 野放しに
しておくわけにはいかない！
I want to know what they're after,
but they're very dangerous.
(綱手)ヤツらの目的も知りたいが
かなりの手練だ。
火ノ国から 絶対に逃がすな！
Don't let them out of the Land of Fire,
no matter what.
Find them without fail and
if you're unable to restrain them,
必ず見つけ出し
身柄の拘束が不可能な場合➡
kill them!
抹殺しろ！ 行け！ 散！
Go!
Dismissed!
I will do my best, and I won't bring
shame to the former Team Asuma.
《いの : 元 アスマ班の名を
汚さないよう…》
We'll do our best,
Shikamaru, Asuma Sensei!
《チョウジ : がんばるからね
シカマル アスマ先生！》
Now then...
(シカマル)さて…。
Okay, we'll start with
the Temple of Fire.
じゃあ オレたちは
火ノ寺からあたるぞ。
Someone has to do it.
誰かが やらなきゃな…。
Let's go.
(アスマ)行くぞ！
Asuma-sensei...
アスマ先生。
なんだ？
What is it?
It seems you were acquainted
with Chiriku from the Temple of Fire.
アンタ 火ノ寺の地陸って人と
知り合いっぽかったが。
Yeah... Didn't I tell you?
あぁ 言ってなかったか？
We used to be brothers-in-arms.
昔の戦友だ。
It was around the time
when I left the Hidden Leaf
オレが 木ノ葉を離れ➡
and was known as one of
the Guardian Shinobi Twelve.
守護忍十二士なんて
呼ばれてた頃のな。
The Temple of Fire is close.
Let's hurry!
火ノ寺は近い！ 急ぐぞ！
The moon sure is beautiful.
(サクラ)月が きれい。
((ヘヘヘ！
はぁ～ サクラちゃんってば
すっげえ！
You're awesome, Sakura-chan!
Just what I'd expect from
the girl I knew you'd be!
(さすが オレの見込んだ女！))
((みんな 変わっていく))
Everyone's changing.
《そう 変わってしまった…》
That's right. Everyone's changed.
《サクラ : ナルトは サスケ君を追いかけて➡
Naruto is continuing with
his training that nobody else can do...
誰にも できないような修業を
続けている》
all to pursue Sasuke-kun.
((イテテテ…。
(サスケ)フン！
アハハ！ ナルトったら))
Oh, Naruto...
《私ができるのは
ほんの小さなことだけ》
I can only do little things for him.
It's not the size of the things
you can do that matters.
((ヤマト : できることの
大きい小さいは 問題じゃないよ。
What's important is the strength
of your feelings for Naruto.
(大切なのは
ナルトを思う気持の大きさでしょ))
流れ星か。
A shooting star, huh?
Sasuke...
サスケ…。
Multi Shadow Clone Jutsu.
多重影分身の術！
はっ！ はっ！ はっ！
はっ！ はっ！
Damn it!
クソッ！
Sasuke...
《サスケ…》
As long as I don't give in
《でもよ オレが折れなきゃ…➡
and keep going without
stopping to rest...
オレが 休まず歩き続けりゃ…➡
I'll arrive at the point where...
いつか たどり着くよな》
Here we go!
いくぞ～！ はっ！
All right!
よっしゃ！
This training is something else, isn't it?
(ヤマト)この修業は
なかなかのもんですね。
Naruto is progressing
so quickly.
あのナルトが こんなに早く…。
No... It's not just because
of this training approach.
(カカシ)いや この修業方法の
おかげばかりじゃないよ。
Sasuke has something
to do with it, too.
(カカシ)サスケが そうさせるんだ。
- We cut the waterfall!
- We really cut it!
滝 切れたってばよ！ マジ 切れた!!
フゥ…。
(カカシ)よくやった。
Well done.
Now we can start development
of your new original Jutsu.
これで 次からは
オリジナルの新術開発に入る。
ハァ ハァ… わかったってば。
Right... I got it...
You okay, Naruto?!
大丈夫か ナルト？
I guess he overdid it a little.
《少し やりすぎたか》
Wh-What is it?
な… なんだ？
は… 腹… 減った…。
I'm... hungry...
You really are... something else.
《本当に
たいしたヤツだよ お前は》
Young people
iiijii na riyuu
I'll always accept your excuses
issai yurusu jakuhai
I summoned the rescue team too
resukuyuu tai mo yonde oita
So
dakara
Please kiss me please kiss me
puriizu kisu mii purizu kisu mi
All night
all night
The magic of a fallen angel or the silly pranks of a little demon
datenshi no mahou ka koakuma no chachi na itazura
Before it gets boring
tsuman naku nacchau mae ni
go and hurl
soore de houre
The bowling ball
bouringu booru
It's a strange existence
kibutsuhason zai nado
I know it already
shouchi no suke
It looks breakable...
kowaresou de
Clear the way with those sloppy emotions
tocchirakatta kanjou de kirihirake yo
ダ～ッ！ カカシ先生 今日も遅刻かよ。
It looks breakable
kowaresou de
まぁ いつものことだけど。
おっ そうだ！
え!?
グフフフ…。
何よ？
(カカシ)いや～ 遅刻 遅刻。
Yet it's not our victory
kowasenai bokura no shouri
ふぇ～ もう１歩たりとも動けん。
いや～ すまないねぇ。
いえ いえ いえ。
Next Episode
Shizune, have we figured out
what they're up to?
ところで
おばあさんの家は まだですか？
Using the twenty platoons,
へい。
ん？ なに～!?
we are currently laying out
a search net
with a radius of 150 kilometers around
the border and the Temple of Fire.
あぁ えらい目にあった。
And... it seems they have not yet
encountered the Akatsuki.
じっとしてて！
今 助けてあげるよ！
(カカシ)どうしたの キミたち？
Why not?
We laid down a search net not
even an ant could crawl through!
(カカシ)ネコ？
-Why haven't they been found yet?!
-Well...
What about the report from Team Asuma
(２人)ありがとう おじちゃん。
(カカシ)お おじちゃん!?
that was heading for
the Temple of Fire?
(２人)じゃあね！
(カカシ)アハハハ…。
Next time: "The Old Monk's Prayer"
The Old Monk's Prayer
あぁ… 今日は なんて日なんだ…。
Kakashi-sensei's late again today?!
たまには いい薬よね。
いい気味じゃ。 ニヒヒ！
Well, it happens all the time.
Oh! I know!
Huh?!
What is it?
Oh, man. I'm late, I'm late.
I can't move another step.
Gee, thank you so much.
It's okay.
By the way,
how much further to your house?
Whaaaat?!
Phew, that was a terrible experience.
Stay right there!
We'll save you now.
What's the matter, guys?
A cat?!
Thanks, old man.
O-Old man...
- Bye.
What a day.
A good lesson for him
once in a while, eh?
Serves him right.